All our difference, let's start talking about string handling in Java, right?
One of the more important concepts that we have to cover, because against strings are
something that you will use every day, not just almost every day, but every single day
in the Java programming language, because that's the use case.
Strings is Java gives us a comprehensive way of dealing with strings.
You will shortly know why I say so, right?
And we start with the Java.land.string class.
Now, what is Java to rely on?
That is slightly short for language, and it is a package which is pretty imported whenever
you write a program in Java.
That is the system class, the string in public static wide main of integer upper classes.
Because all are in Java.land and whatever classes are in the Java.land package, we were
never meant to, or we were never meant to import, right?
We never imported that by, because that's already imported for us.
To take it to make it convenient for us to get started out to the box, to write code
in Java, right?
So they said that all the important classes that we use almost any other day, let's put
that in-land and let's onto import everything that is in Java.land.And one of those important
classes is the Java.land.string class S with a capital SY, because it's a class that
I remember came with the case, right?
And now, two things are often said about strings in Java.
The first is that is strings in Java are immutable, that is string immutability.
The first property is string immutability, that is not changeable, and that means strings
in Java are constants.
That means if you put a value in a string object in Java, it cannot be changed.
It is fixed for all things to come until that is garbage collected, until that is deleted.
So that is strings or string immutability.
Now, let's have a look at why they're immutable and what makes them constant and why
cannot be changed, right?
But first, how do you use the string class in Java simple, right?
A couple of ways to do that, because it's an object, now you know how to use an object.
So you will just go out and say string, let's call it str, obviously, this is not how
we should name our variables, as I've been telling you all through, that as we should all,
we should always be up for better identifiers.
So for now, str works, and I'll say, new string, right?
So if you wrote this kind of a code in your IDE, that is how you would create a new string
object in Java with the string constructor now, right?
And then you will go on and put the value like this, right?
Java still rocks, and you should know now a pair of double quotes is considered a string
object in Java.
So whenever you see a pair of double quotes, it's a string object, and that's how it works,
because str on the left side is of type string, double quotes a string, it's compatible,
your new friend, the compiler is happy, right?
The second way of doing that would have something like this, I'll say string, SD, and
you would have said to new string on the next line, right?
So that is obviously you know it by now, this is declaration, and analyses on two different
lines.
This is declaration and initialization on the same line we have yet on the way.
That is, that is particular to strings, the what you can do is I'll say this is the first
way, this is the second way of defining strings, the third way is just what you will most
likely use always and you just directly say, I'll just call it, for example, my well
equal to delete, that's it.
So no new required, I told you there are situations in Java where even without using the
keyword new, you can still go ahead and create objects.
This is one of them, this is the first way I'm telling you, there is no new, but again
a new string object is created, right?
If it doesn't exist, but more on that later, but for now though that this is another way
and the most preferred way of creating strings in Java, that is the third, right?
And once you do that, we can go ahead and operate on the string and as I told you, it's
a comprehensive class, it has great utility methods defined within the string class and
you can go ahead and just utilize them, I'll just walk you through highlights some of the
common ones.
So for example, now you declared this variable as my value called delete, the first thing
we'll do is for example, I would want to concatenate it.
So you can go ahead and use the concatenation operator, I'll say plus equal to, let's
just say is teaching Java.
And then I'll just say a system without a print ln my Y. Obviously, this is non the proper
syntax, I'm just using the whiteboard to make you understand properly to annotate in
some time we'll go in the right here as well.
So when we say system allowed to create a minor, what is the output that you're expecting?
Think about it, what I told you about strings.
Take a moment, yes, I told you the immutable and if the immutable if there are constants,
this should still print over leave.
But does it when you go ahead and print this and you go ahead and run this on your system,
you will get where it is teaching Java, that means it was in fact concatenated.
So what is going on here?
What is the hype about immutable these string immortability that is once we can put a value,
once we put a value in a string object in Java, we cannot change it.
It's changing and it's printing as well that is just spending the complete thing that
is we'll leave is teaching job, right?
So what on earth is going on here?
So let me make you understand see what happens is now what happens is let's just put
this to the left for string strings in Java, there's a special area of RAM.
The result for just storing string objects, why?
Because we use them a lot and that is called the scp.
Sure, but the string constant pool, right?
It's a pool of string constants.
What happens is when you say string my value equal to let's take it from the third syntax.
So this is something like this, see, my value is your variable and on the heap in the string
constant pool of RAM, you get that object from it.
See, my value is the reference, that's very important for you to understand how you
will change it.
So then you say my value plus equal to is teaching Java.
So what did I say the first step is whenever you say a double course, it's a string object
in Java.
So what does it do?
It goes on to the scp sees if we already have an object with this value, why?
Because they want to effectively, efficiently use strings, string constant memory in Java,
the string handling, because we use a lot of strings in a programming, so they want to efficiently
utilize that.
If it's only there, so no new object would be created, but in our case, it's not there.
So they went ahead and created one more object that is is teaching Java.
And then plus, then caffeinated, remember, this is plus equal to concatenated this with
wallet is teaching Java.
Again, that's not there, they went ahead and created one more.
And what happened is just reassigned this my value that is is equal to the new object
that was created and diagram became like this.
And that is why when you printed system around the prison my bad, you got a lead is teaching
Java, not well.
But you see that, well, this still there, it is not changed a bit.
It's a constant.
I told you there in mutable see and what happened behind the scenes is, until line number
three, you think that you're just dealing with one object that was created right here.
But in five, three objects have been created unintentionally behind the scenes, but efficiently
utilizing the string memory, right?
So that is how it works.
Now we move ahead and then what do you do is you say, my well, that's it.
You want its value in lower case.
You say or in other case, there's a utility method by it because I told you that a lot
of utility methods, right?
You say dot to upper case.
And then you go ahead and print system without the print ln my bad.
So what is the value that you're expecting?
Think about it, right?
We will still get wallet is teaching Java, right?
Or let's do one thing, let's try to keep it small, what I do is, I'll just try to replace
it here.
See, I'll try to replace this first, what I'll do is, I'll say something like this
first, I'll say, after this print ln my value equal to, I'll just say, changed.
So I put the value change.
So what happens?
Obviously, you know, in the Cp, there was one more object created with the value changed
and my well was referring to that now, it's true like this.
So now it has changed and then you say my bad dot upper case, when you say my well,
you still get changed as it was, see capital, all of this and small.
So what is going on here again now, so that means when you say my value to upper case,
it went ahead in the Cp and created one more in upper case, but, and this is a big
part here, you forgot to reassign, because my value is still referring to the current
older value with only the C in capitals, that's why you just get with my well, you still
get this, not the capital one, because this was left on a sign, right? So remember, whenever
you operate on a string, object in Java, you have to reassign or assign it to a new string
variable, right? So we forgot that, that's why we get this older value. If you want the
newer value, always do this. I'll say my value equal and now you will see the diagram like
this, and remember, whenever you are put in a new value or change or operate on a string,
you not forget to reassign, right? So that's just a short intro to how strings work, right?
And we'll just go ahead in our IDE now quickly and just put in this code and much more to
make you understand the different utility methods as it has and what lies in it.